<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>iurisilvio - chrome</title><link href="https://iurisilv.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://iurisilv.io/feed/tag/chrome.feed/atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://iurisilv.io/</id><updated>2012-11-05T00:00:00-02:00</updated><entry><title>Google Analytics memory leak in Chrome</title><link href="https://iurisilv.io/2012/11/google-analytics-memory-leak-in-chrome.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-11-05T00:00:00-02:00</published><updated>2012-11-05T00:00:00-02:00</updated><author><name>Iuri de Silvio</name></author><id>tag:iurisilv.io,2012-11-05:/2012/11/google-analytics-memory-leak-in-chrome.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In last days, after I upgraded to Ubuntu 12.10 (it may be related with the issue or not), I experienced a weird slowness in the whole OS. Using &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;top&lt;/tt&gt;, I found a Chrome tab consuming around 1.2GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a tab with a Google Analytics realtime view. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In last days, after I upgraded to Ubuntu 12.10 (it may be related with the issue or not), I experienced a weird slowness in the whole OS. Using &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;top&lt;/tt&gt;, I found a Chrome tab consuming around 1.2GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a tab with a Google Analytics realtime view. I keep this tab open almost all the time in a machine, so I know it is a memory consuming site, but I never saw something like that. I re-opened the same tab, which started with ~100MB and in a few hours it crashed again after consuming all virtual memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far it was just a memory consuming application, but something is really wrong with Chrome or with Google Analytics. In both cases, it is Google fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thepileof.blogspot.com.br/2012/01/google-chrome-memory-leak-discovered.html"&gt;another report&lt;/a&gt;, but it happened only after a week with Google Analytics realtime running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll report this issue to Chromium project and I'll try to profile this tab with Chrome Developer Tools to get more information about the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at my Google Chrome Task Manager:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Chrome/Google Analytics memory leak" src="https://iurisilv.io/images/google-analytics-memory-leak-in-chrome/task-manager.png" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
</content><category term="issue"></category><category term="chrome"></category></entry><entry><title>Chrome will break extensions backward compatibility</title><link href="https://iurisilv.io/2012/07/chrome-will-break-extensions-backward-compatibility.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-28T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2012-07-28T00:00:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Iuri de Silvio</name></author><id>tag:iurisilv.io,2012-07-28:/2012/07/chrome-will-break-extensions-backward-compatibility.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you develop a Chrome Extension, you should know that. Some days ago, I received a scary red warning during development of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/cgdkiknkffmdbonojkcofooaampcefom"&gt;FunBlocker&lt;/a&gt; Chrome Extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Chrome manifest warning" src="https://iurisilv.io/images/chrome-will-break-extensions-backward-compatibility/manifest-warning.png" style="width: 550px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No problem, I can just follow the rules defined in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/chrome/extensions/manifestVersion.html"&gt;Chrome Extensions Manifest Version&lt;/a&gt; and migrate my manifest to get rid of this warning. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you develop a Chrome Extension, you should know that. Some days ago, I received a scary red warning during development of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/cgdkiknkffmdbonojkcofooaampcefom"&gt;FunBlocker&lt;/a&gt; Chrome Extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Chrome manifest warning" src="https://iurisilv.io/images/chrome-will-break-extensions-backward-compatibility/manifest-warning.png" style="width: 550px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No problem, I can just follow the rules defined in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/chrome/extensions/manifestVersion.html"&gt;Chrome Extensions Manifest Version&lt;/a&gt; and migrate my manifest to get rid of this warning. I just released it and broke my plugin. Why?? It was suposed to Chrome maintain everything up to date and working fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="things-you-should-know"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Things you should know&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can disable Chrome auto updates. Yeah, it is not a good option, but I can not blame the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome Extensions are in fact Chromium extensions. Other Chromium based browsers do not update often and extension developers do not have an easy way to handle that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome will maintain the extension up to date, even if it does not understand the manifest file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading some docs, I found I can set &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/chrome/extensions/manifest.html#minimum_chrome_version"&gt;minimum_chrome_version&lt;/a&gt;, but to be honest my app does not depend of the Chrome version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based in Chrome schedule, Web Store will block new extensions with &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;manifest_version=1&lt;/tt&gt; after Chrome 21 release. I am just maintaining an extension, so it is not a problem for me. Web Store will block updates with &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;manifest_version=1&lt;/tt&gt; after Chrome 23 release, planned to early november 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based in my Analytics data, I have more than 3% of users in browser versions minor than 18 or in Rockmelt, which will not work with manifest upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="my-solution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to maintain &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;manifest_version=1&lt;/tt&gt; as long as possible (maybe early november). In next months, I will add a friendly warning to my options page like &amp;quot;sorry, but this plugin will not receive updates until you update your browser&amp;quot;. After that, I will add &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;minimum_chrome_version=18&lt;/tt&gt; and upgrade the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/chrome/extensions/manifest.html#manifest_version"&gt;manifest_version&lt;/a&gt;. Docs does not recommended to use version 2 in Chrome 17, so 18 is a good number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to be clear, I am not against this manifest upgrade, it is really interesting to improve browser security, but some changes break compatilibity instead of do a painless transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="programming"></category><category term="chrome"></category></entry></feed>